<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
 	<channel>
		<title>Blog | Vanilla Bean Cuisine in Paris | Molly Pisula</title>
		<link>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/</link>
		<description></description>
		<language>en</language>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 13:19:35 -0400</lastBuildDate>
		<docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
		<generator>Sandvox 2.10.1</generator>
		<item>
			<title>Glamping, French-style</title>
			<link>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/glamping-french-style.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are now a mere 2 days from leaving Paris and heading back to the United States, but we have had such fun this last month that I’m dying to document it here so we can re-live every wonderful moment of it when we’re back at &lt;s&gt;boring old&lt;/s&gt; home sweet home. (Can you tell that my feelings about leaving are a little conflicted?) 
					&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, upon the recommendation of friends and all-things-France experts, Gaelle and Nikhil, we decided to get away for a long weekend of upscale camping in the Loire Valley at Huttopia. …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 04:17:45 -0400</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/glamping-french-style.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>An American Cousin in Paris</title>
			<link>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/an-american-cousin-in-paris.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think when the girls look back on their time in Paris, one of their highlights will be when their cousin Joaquin and Auntie Shana came to visit. For months, “I miss Cuzzie!!” was a recurring refrain here, and Piper and Ruby talked incessantly about what they would do when Joj came to visit. I’d say we knocked it out of the park. …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 01:50:43 -0400</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/an-american-cousin-in-paris.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>School Life in Paris</title>
			<link>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/school-life-in-paris.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the things that had me in the most panic last fall as we were planning our move was where the girls would go to school. I spent weeks researching schools and reaching out to friends of friends for recommendations. In the end, we decided that an English-speaking international school would be best, as dropping the kids midway through the year into a French-speaking school for only 6 months seemed pretty cruel. …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 08:24:13 -0400</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/school-life-in-paris.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Building New Pathways</title>
			<link>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/building-new-pathways.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest challenges in moving to a foreign country is having to rebuild all those life pathways you have created over years and years. How long have you used your favorite brand of toothpaste, or mascara, or cereal? How do you know where to buy your clothes or kids’ shoes or birthday party decorations? Moving to another country is to disrupt those worn pathways almost entirely, to give yourself a reset for all those routines you fall into without really questioning why. 
					&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 08:51:10 -0400</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/building-new-pathways.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Bucket List</title>
			<link>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/bucket-list.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just 7 weeks left in Paris, and suddenly I feel like the days are being ripped off a day-of-the-year calendar in fast motion like in the movies. There is still so much I want to see and do (and eat!) before we leave, while at the same time, lunches need to be packed, and laundry needs to be done, someone just yelled “but it’s not FAAAAAIIR! …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 06:53:08 -0400</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/bucket-list.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Simple Entertaining</title>
			<link>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/simple-entertaining.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;At home, back in the States, entertaining is one of my great pleasures in life. I can spend hours planning menus and weekend time prepping dishes (or parts of dishes) to freeze before the event. I create detailed timelines so I can keep track of when each step for each dish needs to be completed, sometimes backing up a few days in advance of the party. …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 09:29:08 -0400</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/simple-entertaining.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Family “Vacation” in Italy: Parte Due</title>
			<link>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/family-vacation-in-italy-2.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;On our last morning in Rome, we took a taxi to the train station and had no problems finding our high-speed train to Venice. We located our seats, stowed our luggage, and sat down to enjoy a three-hour train ride through the Italian countryside—this is the way to travel, people! The weather became progressively more overcast and rainy as we rode, but we still enjoyed seeing the small Tuscan farmhouses and rolling hills as we flew by at well over 100mph. …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 08:23:48 -0400</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/family-vacation-in-italy-2.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Family “Vacation” in Italy: Part 1</title>
			<link>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/family-vacation-in-italy.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Does the word “vacation” conjure up images of white-sand beaches, fruity drinks with umbrellas in them, and hours spent lying on a chaise by the ocean with a stack of books next to you? Nothing to do, nowhere to be, and the hardest decision you have to make is what to order for dinner? That sounds nice, doesn’t it? Well that is not what happens when you vacation with your children—anywhere, really, but certainly not when you travel abroad with them. …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 10:03:03 -0400</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/family-vacation-in-italy.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Visit to Giverny</title>
			<link>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/a-visit-to-giverny.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;There’s a reason for the cliché about Paris in the springtime. In March and the beginning of April, it seemed like leaves were appearing back on the trees at an interminably slow pace, patches of flowers here and there suddenly in bloom, one fountain filled and turned on, and then another. And then suddenly the end of April arrived, and the gardens and parks exploded into color. …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 09:43:27 -0400</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/a-visit-to-giverny.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>In Defense of American Food</title>
			<link>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/in-defense-of-american-food.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not long after moving to Paris, I was convinced that I had found food heaven. Quaint little bistros on every corner, fresh baguettes, biting into a croissant or pain au chocolat still warm from the oven. I would move here for the cheese shops alone. And the farmers markets that pop up every day of the week in different parts of the city (Tuesdays, I pass one on my way to and from the girls’ school when I go to read with Ruby’s class. …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 05:55:51 -0400</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/in-defense-of-american-food.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Easter in Paris</title>
			<link>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/easter-in-paris.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back home in the States, my girls absolutely love Easter. We have a neighborhood egg hunt every year in the park near our house, we dye Easter eggs with my mom, sister, and nephew, and we always have a family get-together where we eat great food and hunt for eggs in my sister’s backyard. Come to think of it, I love it too. So when Easter season rolled around here in Paris, the girls got very excited, and also very concerned that Easter might not be celebrated here (they were a little scarred by the almost total ignoring of Valentine’s Day here). …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 09:31:25 -0400</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/easter-in-paris.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>In Search of the World’s Best Beer</title>
			<link>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/in-search-of-the-worlds.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the grand and wonderful things about living in Paris is that the travel options from here are just so incredible, especially to Americans like us where it takes a pretty big effort to get to another country. Hop on a train, take a short flight, or head out on a drive, and here in Europe you can be speaking a different language and experiencing an entirely different culture within hours! …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 02:40:28 -0400</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/in-search-of-the-worlds.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Spring vs. Smog</title>
			<link>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/spring-vs-smog.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whispers of spring here are everywhere. Every time I go out for a jog, I see a patch of flowers that I hadn’t noticed before (hello forsythias!), or count a few more cherry blossoms opening on the patches of trees interspersed along the Champs de Mars. (Who knew there would be so many flowers that remind me of springtime back home in DC?!) …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 10:21:43 -0400</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/spring-vs-smog.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Baking for a Crowd</title>
			<link>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/baking-for-a-crowd.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;There’s nothing like baking 75 brownies and 250 cookies to show you just how small your kitchen actually is. And your oven, for that matter. Why would I do that to myself, you ask? Let me back up. Not long after we made plans to move here, I heard about the group &lt;a href="http://www.messageparis.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Message&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a network of English-speaking moms and moms-to-be (and a few dads) here in Paris—there are meetups planned all across the city for moms with kids of different ages, working moms, and special interests. …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 10:52:28 -0400</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/baking-for-a-crowd.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Trip to Deauville</title>
			<link>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/a-trip-to-deauville.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the last weekend of Les Vacances, we decided to head out of the city for a few days. With not much chance of getting somewhere warm within a short train ride, we decided on the seaside town of Deauville, in Normandy. Friday afternoon, we took the metro to the Gare Saint-Lazare, and got on a 2-hour train ride to Deauville. It was our first time riding the rails, but we muddled through the inevitable confusions about how to find which track the train was on, and how to determine the car number on the train cars for our reserved seats. …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 10:52:25 -0400</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/a-trip-to-deauville.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Les Vacances, Part I</title>
			<link>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/les-vacances-part-i.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’ve had our first taste of the Parisian school schedule, and the kids likey. The parents, perhaps not quite so much. What do you do with 2 weeks off at the end of February, where almost every place within a few hours drive is equally cold, windy, and rainy? In our case, you send in reinforcements! Grandma and Grandpa P arrived a couple of days into the vacation, and we used our time off to play tourist around the city. …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 09:28:26 -0500</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/les-vacances-part-i.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Chicken Soup for the Soul</title>
			<link>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/chicken-soup-for-the-soul.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember my &lt;a href="http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/the-fog-lifts.html"&gt;earlier post on roast chicken&lt;/a&gt;? Here’s the second reason why this is one of my favorite family meals: leftovers. Depending on the size of your chicken, and the amount of veggies you cram into your pot (I play fast and loose with the recipe quantities), you can easily get another good meal out of this dish. But do you ever find yourself at the point with your chicken carcass where most of the good meat has been picked off, but there’s still enough there to do something with? …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 11:33:09 -0500</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/chicken-soup-for-the-soul.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Fog Lifts</title>
			<link>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/the-fog-lifts.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is nothing like being sick for making you want to go running home and cry for your mommy. We knew it would happen—the stress of the move and living in a new city, the winter gloom here, and of course, being exposed to lots of new and wonderful germs. Just like back home, flu season has hit Paris hard, and the streets and metros are filled with people coughing and sneezing. …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 09:35:36 -0500</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/the-fog-lifts.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How to Spend 5 Hours at the Eiffel Tower</title>
			<link>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/how-to-spend-5-hours-at-the.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;(…and I don’t mean waiting in line.) The day we arrived in Paris we had our first Eiffel Tower sighting. From our apartment in the 16th arrondissement the Tower is just a 10-minute walk (maybe 15 on kid legs), so even jet-lagged and overwhelmed, we made our way there to prove we had, in fact, made it to Paris. The next day we made it across the Seine to actually stand under the tower, but it was completely packed, being that it was just a couple of days before New Year’s. …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 09:45:02 -0500</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/how-to-spend-5-hours-at-the.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Lunch to Feel Good About</title>
			<link>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/a-lunch-to-feel-good-about.html</link>
			<description>
				&lt;div class="article-summary"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m always on the lookout for healthy lunch recipes. I don’t know about you, but it’s much easier for me to be a careful eater for breakfast and lunch, which then gives me license to splurge on dinner. What’s that you say? You say there is absolutely no dietary evidence supporting that assertion? Well who asked you anyway. For me, the combination of feeling virtuous during the day while still contemplating the wine, cheese, and chocolate I deserve to eat for dinner and dessert is pretty appealing. 
					&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 07:22:05 -0500</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.vanillabeancuisine.com/paris/blog/a-lunch-to-feel-good-about.html</guid>
            
			
		</item>
 	</channel>
</rss>